丁丁历险记
<font color=#ffff0f>独角兽号的秘密
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译创作
最新最快的HR-HDTV 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译:  zhanginfo  le_grand_bleu  gkall  大米稀饭
校对:  rosemaryai  总监:  可乐嘻嘻  后期:  blueliongb
■
马上就好  先生
Very nearly there, sir.
看你有点眼熟  我以前给你画过像吗
I have to say, your face is familiar. Have I drawn you before?
画过几次
Occasionally.
对啊  我还在报纸上见过你
Of course! I've seen you in the newspaper.
-你是报导新闻的  -我是写新闻的记者
- You're a reporter? - I'm a journalist.
别急  白雪  就好了
Be patient, Snowy, not much longer.
真抱歉
I do beg your pardon.
好了
There.
画得还挺像吧
I believe I have captured something of your likeness.
不错
Not bad!
你看呢  白雪
What do you think, Snowy?
白雪
Snowy!
给您钱  先生
There you are, sir.
又跑哪儿去了
Now where's he run off to?
有情况吗
Anything?
没有
Nothing.
白雪
Snowy!
你去哪儿了啊
Where have you been?
又去欺负猫咪了
Chasing cats again?
白雪  看这个
Snowy, look at this!
三个桅杆
Triple masted.
双层甲板  五十门火炮
Double decks. Fifty guns.
多漂亮啊
Isn't she a beauty?
绝对珍稀的船模
That's a very unique specimen.
某位老船长的遗物
That is from an old sea captain's estate.
独角兽号
"The Unicorn."
对  独角兽号  帆船时代的战舰之王
Unicorn. Man o'war sailing ship.
年代非常久远  十六世纪的
It's very old, that is 16th century.
我记得是十七世纪
17th, I would think.
-查理一世时代  -是查理二世
- Reign of Charles I. - Charles II.
没错  是查理二世
That's what I said, Charles II.
驰骋世界的无敌战舰
As fine a ship as ever sailed the seven seas.
小伙子  这可是难得一见的东西
You won't find another one of these, mate.
只卖两英镑
And it's only two quid.
-我出一镑  -成交
- I'll give you a pound. - Done!
拿好了啊
Gently does it.
劳驾
Excuse me!
拿好  慢点
Here you go. Careful.
伙计  这船多少钱
Hey, bud, how much for the boat?
不好意思  刚卖给这个年轻人
I'm sorry, I just sold it to this young gent.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
你出了多少  我加倍给你
Tell me what you paid and I'll give you double.
-加倍?  -谢谢  可我不卖
- Double? - Thanks. But it's not for sale.
听着  年轻人  我是想帮你
Look, kid, I'm trying to help you out.
你不清楚其中利害
I don't think you realise this,
你就要大祸临头了
but you're about to walk into a whole mess of danger.
什么祸
What kind of danger?
我警告你  别要这船
I'm warning you, get rid of the boat
趁着还不晚  别惹麻烦
and get out while you still can.
那帮人不好惹
These people do not play nice.
哪帮人
What people?
真漂亮
Wonderful!
太漂亮了
It's just wonderful.
不用包了  我就这么拿走
Don't bother wrapping it, I'll take it as is.
我开支票可以吗
Does anybody object if I pay by cheque?
您要想买得和这小伙子商量
If you want to buy it, you'll have to talk to the kid.
明白了
I see.
那就让他开个价儿吧
Well, let the kid name his price.
随便开价儿
"Name his price"?
我倒腾这些小玩意儿十年了
Ten years I've been flogging bric-a-brac
结果眼皮底下丢了这种好买卖
and I miss "name your price" by one bleedin' minute!
抱歉  我和另一个买主也说了
I'm sorry. I already explained to the other gentleman.
美国佬  擦头油还不穿袜子
American he was. All hair oil and no socks.
这东西不卖
It's not for sale.
那就请你帮个忙
Then let me appeal to your better nature.
最近我刚买下马林斯派克别墅
I have recently acquired Marlinspike Hall,
而这条船  我想你也知道
and this ship, as I'm sure you're aware,
也是遗物一部分
was once part of the estate.
故去那个船长的
Of the late sea captain?
他们家族时运不济  家产折腾得精光
The family fell upon hard times. Lost everything.
此后一蹶不振  霉运连连
They've been living in a cloud of bad luck ever since.
这家人代代都酗酒
We are talking generations
而且行为怪异
of drinking and irrational behaviour...
抱歉
I'm sorry.
但我说过了  这船不卖
But as I told you before, it's not for sale.
祝您愉快  先生
Good day to you, sir.
那年轻人叫什么名字
That young man, what's his name?
他  谁都认识他  他是丁丁
Him? Everybody knows him. That's Tintin.
这船怎么回事
What is it about this ship?
怎么引起那么多人的兴趣
Why has it attracted so much attention?
到底里面藏着什么秘密呢
What secrets do you hold?
放大镜在哪儿
Where is that magnifying glass?
记着明明放在
I could have sworn it was...
《记者丁丁披露黑帮真相》
《记者揭幕犯罪团伙》
能放在哪儿呢
Where could it possibly be?
《丁丁追回博物馆被窃国宝》
《权杖安然重归陛下》
白雪  你看到没
Snowy, you haven't seen the...
放哪儿了
Where is it?
谢谢
Thank you.
别  白雪
No, Snowy!
瞧你干的好事
Look what you did.
你把船弄坏了
You broke it!
臭狗狗
Bad dog!
这船肯定有古怪
Something happened on this ship.
我们去个可能找到答案的地方
And we're going to the one place that could have the answer.
走吧  白雪
Come on, Snowy.
在这里
Here it is.
马林斯派克别墅的主人法兰西斯·阿道克爵士
"Sir Francis Haddock of Marlinspike Hall,
厄运缠身的独角兽号最后一任船长
the last captain of the ill-fated Unicorn.
1676年该船由巴巴多斯起锚
"The ship set sail from Barbados in 1676
遭遇航海史上最不幸的海难之一
"on one of the most ruinous voyages in maritime history.
船只未抵达目的地
"Ship never reached destination.
受到海盗攻击  仅一名船员幸存
"Attacked by pirates, all hands lost except for one survivor.
弗朗西斯爵士获救回国后
"When Sir Francis was rescued and returned home,
认为其族姓遭受了诅咒
"he was convinced his name had been cursed.
独角兽号装货单显示
"The Unicorn's manifest stated
船上载有一批
"that it was carrying a
运往欧洲的朗姆酒和烟草
cargo of rum and tobacco bound for Europe,
但一直有人认为  船上载有一批神秘货物
"But it was long claimed the ship was carrying a secret cargo."
船上装的到底是什么呢  白雪
What was the ship carrying, Snowy?
历史学家几经努力
"Historians have tried and failed
仍无法查清那趟死亡之旅中发生了什么
to discover what happened on that fatal voyage,
但弗朗西斯爵士的遗言称
"but Sir Francis' last words,
"唯真正阿道克族人可洞悉独角兽号之隐秘"
"'only a true Haddock will discover the secret of the Unicorn."'
我肯定忽略了什么  白雪
I've missed something, Snowy.
我们得仔细看看那艘船模
We need to take a closer look at that model.
肯定不在了
Of course it's gone!
我怎么这么蠢
How could I be so stupid?
你怎么进去的
How'd you do that?
真聪明
Clever boy.
一面族徽
A coat of arms.
怎么看着有点眼熟
Why does that look familiar?
等一下
Hang on a minute.
里面的鱼
That fish!
阿道克就是黑线鳕鱼的意思
It's a haddock.
对啊  马林斯派克别墅是阿道克家族的祖业
Of course! Marlinspike Hall is the old Haddock estate.
白雪
Snowy!
好样的  白雪
Well done, Snowy!
好狗狗
Good boy.
这下好了
Well, well, well.
看来找到窃贼了
It seems we've caught our thief.
欢迎来到马林斯派克别墅
Welcome to Marlinspike Hall.
我看到你溜进来
I see you let yourself in.
我来取回自己的东西
I came to retrieve my property.
抱歉  听不懂你说什么
I'm sorry, I'm not sure I follow you.
你自己明白
I think you do.
不到一小时前  这条船在我家被盗
This ship was stolen from my apartment less than an hour ago.
恐怕你弄错了  丁丁先生
I'm afraid you're mistaken, Mr. Tintin.
怎么会错  这船是我的
There's no mistake. It belongs to me.
你肯定吗
Are you sure?
当然肯定
Of course I'm sure.
我买回家后放在起居室的柜架上
I took it home, I put it on a cabinet in the living room,
后来白雪追猫时又把它碰翻
and then Snowy chased the cat and knocked it over,
掉在...地上
and it fell.
这不是我那条船
This isn't my ship.
当然不是
No. Indeed.
对不起
I'm sorry.
-看着一模一样  -眼见也未必为实
- It looks identical. - Well, looks can be deceiving.
是这样  可我弄不明白
Yes, indeed. But I don't understand!
为什么法朗西斯爵士要做两条一模一样的船
Why did Sir Francis make two ships exactly alike?
你都有一个了  干嘛还要另一个
And you have one already. Why do you want another?
船模里有什么会招来窃贼呢
What is it about this model that would cause someone to steal it?
天哪  怎么这么多问题
Goodness me, why so many questions?
职业习惯
It's my job.
这里可能藏着故事  我的职业就是这个
There could be a story here. That's what I do, you see.
这里没什么秘密可言
Well, it's no great mystery.
法朗西斯·阿道克爵士嗜酒成性  是个不可救药的无赖
Sir Francis Haddock was a drunkard and a hopeless reprobate.
他注定失败
He was doomed to fail,
而且把这悲剧传给了子嗣
and he bequeathed that failure to his sons.
那是真的了  阿道克家族被诅咒了
So it's true! The Haddock line is cursed.
-你还发现什么了  -有什么值得发现吗
- What else have you found out? - What is there to find?
那得看你要找什么
That depends what you're looking for.
我要找到答案  萨卡林先生
I'm looking for answers, Mr. Sakharine.
你找错地方了
You're looking in the wrong place.
不早了
It's late.
你该回去了
I think you should go home.
这边请  先生
This way, sir.
真遗憾  先生
It's a pity, sir.
什么
I'm sorry?
您那只船模上断掉的桅杆  先生
That the mast broke on your model ship, sir.
希望您找齐了所有的零件
I hope you found all the pieces.
有些东西很容易丢
Things are so easily lost.
内斯特  你去哪儿了
Nestor! Where are you?
晚安  先生
Good night, sir.
有些东西很容易丢
Some things are easily lost.
他说这个什么意思  白雪
What did he mean by that, Snowy?
他想告诉我什么
What was he trying to tell me?
有些东西很容易丢
Some things are easily lost.
白雪
Snowy!
天啊
Great snakes!
怎么了  白雪
What is it, Snowy?
这是什么
What's this?
原来是桅杆里的东西
This was in the mast!
好狗狗  白雪
Good boy, Snowy.
三兄弟联手
"Three brothers joined.
三艘独角兽号同行
"Three Unicorns in company
扬帆于正午  太阳将揭示一切
"sailing in the noonday sun will speak.
因这得自于光  而光将破晓
"For 'tis from the light that light will dawn.
照耀鹰之十字
"And then shines forth the Eagle's Cross."
这些符号什么意思
What are these markings?
某种密文吗
Some kind of secret language or code?
讲不通
It makes no sense.
不过这正说明了屋子为什么被翻个遍
But it does explain why they ransacked the flat.
他们想找这个却没找到
They were looking for this, and they didn't find it.
也就是说
Which means
他们还要再来
they'll be back.
不知道他在哪里  大概出去了吧
No, I don't know where he is, dearie. I think he's gone out.
而且  已经很晚了
And anyway, it's after dark,
丁丁先生从来不愿
and Mr. Tintin is most particular
过了睡觉时间会见访客
about not admitting visitors after bedtime.
我要回去喝热巧克力
I have to go back to my cocoa.
一本好书加上一杯热巧克力
I've got a very good book and a cup of cocoa.
真是太棒了
It's really lovely!
谢谢您  芬奇太太  我来吧
Thank you, Mrs. Finch. I can look after this.
小伙子  是你吗  开开门
Hey, kid, is that you? Open the door.
你想干嘛
What do you want?
听着  没办法了  那人马上就回来
Look, the game is up. He's gonna be back.
我知道他要找那几条船  可我发誓
Now, I know he wanted those boats, but I swear to God,
我真没想到他会为此杀人
I never thought he'd kill anyone over it!
谁  你说这人是谁
Who? Who are you talking about?
我是想告诉你  你现在处境危险
I'm trying to tell you that your life is in danger.
说  那人是谁
Answer me! Who?
芬奇太太  门口有人中枪
Mrs. Finch! A man's been shot on our doorstep!
-怎么又这样  -快叫救护车
- Not again. - Call an ambulance!
不  白雪
No, Snowy!
能听到吗
Can you hear me?
你能...
Can you...
被害人名叫巴纳比·道斯
The victim's name was Barnaby Dawes.
国际刑警组织资深探员
He was one of the top agents at Interpol,
但其调查对象尚不清楚
but we haven't got a clue what he was working on.
没错  汤普森  完全不清楚
Quite right, Thompson. We're completely clueless.
国际刑警组织那边没别的线索吗
Interpol doesn't have any other leads?
别急  丁丁  我们还在处理文书
Steady on, Tintin. We're still filling out the paperwork.
警察工作又不全是惊险刺激
Police work's not all glamour and guns.
还有很多的文书工作
There's an awful lot of filing.
那我可能有些线索
Well, I might have something for you.
道斯失去意识前试图告诉我什么事
Before he lost consciousness, Dawes tried to tell me something,
我看他是在拼一个单词
and I think he was spelling out a word.
b-o-u
"...b- o-u
d-j-a-n
"d-j-a-n.
卡拉布朗
"Karaboudjan."
Karaboudjan!
你知道什么意思吗
Does that mean anything to you?
天啊  太不可思议了
Great Scotland Yard! That's extraordinary!
怎么了
What is?
沃辛顿在搞礼帽半价促销
Worthington's have a half-price sale on bowler hats!
搞什么  汤姆森  案子要紧
Really, Thomson! This is hardly the time.
-天啊  -怎么样
- Great Scotland Yard! - What is it?
手杖也半价啦
Canes are half-price, too!
你俩到底想不想要这物证了
Are you going to take charge of this evidence?
当然要
Positively.
别担心  丁丁  放心交给我们
Never fear, Tintin, the evidence is safe with us!
汤姆森  你在哪儿
Thomson? Where are you?
我已经下楼了  你赶紧跟上
Well, I'm already downstairs. Do try to keep up.
等等  你们忘了拿这个
Wait! You dropped this.
天哪  汤姆森  小心物证
Good heavens, Thomson! Look after the evidence, man.
抱歉  汤普森  我想别的事来着
Sorry, Thompson. My mind is on other things.
对  二指窃贼
Yes. Our light-fingered larcenist.
-什么  -就是扒手
- What? - The pickpocket.
他可料不到我会有这手
He has no idea what's coming.
来  丁丁  掏我的钱夹
Go on, Tintin, take my wallet.
没错  超强橡皮筋
Yes, industrial strength elastic.
真有办法
Very resourceful.
恰恰相反  只是小孩子把戏
On the contrary. It was childishly simple.
没错  小孩子把戏
Simply childish, I agree.
-丁丁  -丁丁
- Tintin. - Tintin.
两位慢走
Gentlemen.
说真的  我认为他已经跑远了
Mind you, I expect he's miles away by now.
你是说小偷吗
I presume you're referring to the pickpocket?
对  我是说  他感觉到我们就要抓到他了
Yes. I mean, knowing we're just a few steps behind him.
白雪  怎么了  看到什么了
Snowy, what is it, boy? What do you see?
估计你不太想喝茶吧
I don't suppose you'd fancy a cup of tea?
正相反  我很想喝
You're quite mistaken. I'd love one.
我请
My treat.
-可逮住你了  -你个混蛋
- I've got you now! - You devil!
站住  警察
Stop, in the name of the law!
抓住了
Got you!
那边怎么了
What's going on down there?
来  白雪
Come on, Snowy!
-真对不起  -抱歉  先生
- I do beg your pardon. - Sorry, sir!
小偷  丁丁  贼跑了
The pickpocket, Tintin! He's getting away!
我的钱包
My wallet!
被偷了
It's gone!
快  白雪  追上他
Come on! Snowy, after him!
别跑
Stop! Wait!
-好了  -别着急
- Got you! - Steady on.
人不见了
I've lost him!
你们必须找到我钱包
You must find my wallet.
非常重要  我必须把钱包拿回来
It's very important. I have to get it back.
放心吧  交给我们这样的专业人士
And you will. Leave it to the professionals.
虽然纸条丢了
We've lost the scroll.
可题材还在
But we haven't lost the story.
卡拉布朗
"Karaboudjan."
这是个亚美尼亚词  那就是线索  白雪
It's an Armenian word. That's our lead, Snowy.
巴纳比·道斯说我们身处险境时
What was Barnaby Dawes trying
究竟想告诉我们什么
to tell us when he said our lives were in danger?
-丁丁先生  -我是
- Mr. Tin... Tin? - Yes.
-你的包裹  -我什么也没订啊
- Delivery for you. - But I didn't order anything.
因为要运的就是你
Well, that's because it's you that's getting delivered!
快  弄进车里
Quick, get him in the van!
滚开  你这条疯狗
Get off me, you confounded mutt!
它咬我
He bit me!
快
Quick!
甩开它
Get him off!
甩下去  碾死它
Shake him off, then run him over!
码头方向
放在右舷
I want this on the starboard side!
没有  搜你那边
Not here. Look your side.
等等
Hang on.
-没有  -搜那个口袋  汤姆
- Nothing. - Well, check that pocket, Tom.
这个我搜过了  的确没有
No, I've looked in this one already, I'm sure of it.
看看他袜子里
Well, have a look in his socks.
-找到了吗  -他身上没有
- Have you found it? - He doesn't have it.
不在他身上  头儿  不在这儿
It's not on him, boss. It's not here.
-不在这儿  那在哪儿  -什么在哪儿
- Not here? Then where is it? - Where's what?
没工夫和你玩  我要独角兽号里的纸条
I am tired of your games. The scroll, from the Unicorn.
像这样的纸片
A piece of paper like this!
你是说那首诗
You mean the poem?
是
Yes.
-古英语写的诗  -对
- The poem written in Old English. - Yes.
-装在小管子里的  -没错
- It was inside a cylinder. - Yes.
-藏在桅杆里那个  -就是那个
- Concealed in the mast. - Yes!
我没有
I don't have it.
你肯定知道纸条的价值  不然拿走干嘛
You know the value of that scroll. Why else would you take it?
两条船  两张纸  都是谜题的一部分
Two ships and two scrolls, both part of a puzzle.
你已经得到一个了  但你还要另一个
You have one, you need the other.
但你要的不是纸条  是别的
But that's not it. There's something else.
无论你帮不帮我  我都会找到
I will find it, with or without your help.
你得好好想想你对我到底有多大用处
You need to think about exactly how useful you are to me.
-我们先起航再收拾他  -是  先生
- We'll deal with him on the way. - Aye-aye, sir.
把事情办好
Hold this course.
白雪
Snowy!
看见你我也高兴
It's good to see you, too.
你能把这些绳子咬断码
See if you can chew through these ropes.
他在撒谎  纸条一定在他身上
He's lying! He must have the scroll.
现在问题是他把纸条藏哪了
The question is, what has he done with it?
我们搜遍了他全身  老大
We searched him all over, boss.
你们给我回去想办法让他开口
I want you to go back down there and make him talk.
哪怕把他身上每根骨头都打断
Break every bone in his body if you have to!
太狠了点吧
That's nasty.
你清楚其中利害  你清楚我们在干什么
You know the stakes. You know what we're playing for.
叫你干什么你就干
Just do it!
萨卡林先生  先生  不好了
Mr. Sakharine! Mr. Sakharine! All hell has broken loose!
出大事了  船长醒了
It's a disaster! The captain has come around.
-什么  -他醒了
- What? - He's conscious.
他指控您叛变
He's accusing you of mutiny.
他说是您让全体船员都背叛他
He says you turned the crew against him.
听起来他又醒酒了
Sounds like he's sobered up again.
别傻站着  再给他拿一瓶酒
Well, don't just stand there. Get him another bottle.
是  先生
Aye, sir!
好了
Okay.
-晃一下就行  卡住了  -晃
- Jiggle it a bit, it's just stuck. - Jiggle?
这样
Here.
干嘛呢  让开
What are you doing? Get off!
不是卡住了  你个白痴
It's not stuck, you idiot.
他从里面把门闩上了
He's bolted it from the inside!
你想跟我们玩玩是吧  丁丁
So you want to play like that then, do you, Tintin?
去拿炸药来
Get the TNT.
破板条箱  绳子  香槟
Broken crates. Rope. Champagne.
还能找到什么  白雪
What else do we have, Snowy?
肯定有别的招能打开这门
There are other ways to open this door.
抓到你就用你的肠子擦甲板
They'll be swabbing the decks with your innards when we're done with you.
给我
Give it here.
-别动  -什么
- Don't move. - What...
咱们上
Let's go!
我来抓住他
Let me have him!
他有枪
He's got a big shooter!
他打中我了
He got me!
停火
Hold your fire.
他不在  逃跑了
He ain't here. He's vanished.
他藏起来了
He's hiding.
搜船  马上
Search the ship. Quickly!
苏门答腊大老鼠
A giant rat of Sumatra!
你以为你能偷偷溜进来
So, you thought you could sneak in behind me
趁我不备偷袭我吗
and catch me with my trousers down, huh?
我更希望你有所防备
I'd rather you kept your trousers on,
对你来说都一样
if it's all the same to you.
我知道你玩什么把戏  你跟他们一伙的
I know your game. You're one of them.
什么
Sorry?
他们派你来杀我
They sent you here to kill me, huh?
听着  我根本不认识你
Look, I don't know who you are!
他就打算这么杀死我
That's how he's planned to bump me off.
派一个娃娃脸刺客让我横死在床
Murdered in my bed by a baby-faced assassin!
刺客  听着  你完全搞错了
Assassin? Look, you've got it all wrong.
我是被一伙强盗绑架来的
I was kidnapped by a gang of thugs.
那个猪猡
The filthy swine.
他策反了我所有的水手
He's turned the whole crew against me!
谁
Who?
一个起了个嗲名的苦瓜脸
A sour-faced man with a sugary name.
他把我所有的水手都收买了  所有的
He's bought them all off, every last man.
是萨卡林
Sakharine!
没人能抢走我的船
Nobody takes my ship!
你是船长吗
You're the captain?
我当然是船长  我还能是谁
Of course I'm the captain. Who else could I be?
我被锁在这个屋子里好几天了
I've been locked in this room for days
只有威士忌来抚慰我受伤的灵魂
with only whisky to sustain my mortal soul.
我以为门锁了
Well, I assumed it was locked.
显然没有
Well, it's not.
失陪了
Now, you must excuse me.
他们要是找到我  肯定会杀了我
If they find me here, they'll kill me.
我得继续逃跑
I have to keep moving.
努力从这个酒气冲天行驶缓慢的破船里逃出去
Try and find my way off this drunken tub.
破船  破船
"Tub"? Tub?
他敢管这叫"破船"
Tub?
-多谢  -不谢
- Thanks. - Pleasure.
顺便说一下  我叫丁丁
I'm Tintin, by the way.
我叫阿切博尔德·阿道克
Haddock. Archibald Haddock.
在甲板上面有一艘大艇  跟我来
There's a longboat up on deck. Follow me.
等一下
Hang on a second.
你说你姓阿道克吗
Did you say "Haddock"?
你怎么让他们跑了
How could you let them escape?
找到他们  找到他们俩
Find them. Find them both.
不用担心  长官  我们一定宰了他们
Don't worry, we'll kill them, sir.
不行
No.
你可以干掉那个男孩  阿道克必须活着
You can kill the boy. Not Haddock.
什么  他就是个一无是处的老醉鬼
What? He's just a hopeless old soak.
我们早就该杀了他
We should've killed him long since.
你以为我选择
You think it's an accident
阿道克的船  阿道克的船员
that I chose Haddock's ship, Haddock's crew,
和阿道克这靠不住的大副是巧合吗
Haddock's treacherous first mate?
没有什么是巧合
Nothing is an accident.
我和阿道克船长渊源很深
We go back a long way, Captain Haddock and I.
我们有一笔账没算清
We've unfinished business.
这次  我要让他付出代价
And this time, I'm going to make him pay.
在这条走廊头上
We have to reach a locked door at
有一扇上锁的门  很棘手
the end of this corridor. This is gonna be tricky.
你不会碰巧跟住在马林斯派克别墅的
You wouldn't happen to be related
阿道克家族有亲戚关系吧
to the Haddocks of Marlinspike Hall, would you?
你为什么问这个
Why do you ask?
这是我报导的第一个故事
It's for a story I've been working on.
一艘在巴巴多斯沿岸的古老沉船
An old shipwreck that happened off the coast of Barbados.
一艘军舰
A man o'war.
三桅杆  五十门炮
Triple masted. Fifty guns.
关于独角兽号你都知道什么
What do you know of the Unicorn?
知道得不多  所以我才问你
Not a lot. That's why I'm asking you.
只有我们家族的人才知道这艘船的秘密
The secret of that ship is known only to my family!
这秘密被一代一代的传下来
It's been passed down from generation to generation.
我的祖父在临死之前亲自告诉我那个传说
My granddaddy himself, with his dying breath, told me the tale.
然后呢
And?
没了
Gone.
什么叫"没了"
What do you mean, gone?
他挂掉的时候我太难过了
I was so upset when he kicked the bucket,
只好借酒浇愁
I had no choice but to drown my sorrows.
等我早上醒来的时候
When I woke up in the morning,
什么都没了  什么都忘了
it was gone! I'd forgotten it all.
-全忘了  -一干二净
- Everything? - Every last word.
你家里还有其他亲人吗
Well, is there somebody else in your family?
没准他们知道
Maybe they would know.
弗朗西斯爵士有三个儿子
Sir Francis had three sons.
除了我这一支都没有后代
All but my bloodline failed.
我是阿道克家族最后的血脉
I am the last of the Haddocks!
你刚刚说三个儿子
Did you say three sons?
下去搜搜
Let's check below!
谁找到阿道克就赏一瓶朗姆酒
There is a bottle of rum for the man who finds Haddock.
还得杀了那个男孩  希望我先找到
And kill the boy. Hope I find him first.
什么声音
What's that?
你又出现幻听了
You're hearing things.
闭嘴  阿里
Quiet, Ali.
那什么都没有
There's nothing there.
上去看看
Let's go up.
我知道萨卡林在找什么了
I know what Sakharine's looking for.
你念叨什么呢
What are you raving on about?
是写在纸条上的东西
It was written on the scroll.
"三兄弟联手
"Three brothers joined.
"三艘独角兽号同行
"Three Unicorns in company
扬帆于正午  太阳将揭示一切"
sailing in the noonday sun will speak."
真的吗
Really?
弗朗西斯爵士不只制作了两个模型
Sir Francis didn't make two models of the Unicorn.
而是三个
He made three!
每个儿子都有一艘船
Three ships for three sons.
太对了
Excellent!
萨卡林在找第三艘模型船
Sakharine's after the third model ship.
真麻烦  有人把门锁上了
Barnacles! Someone's locked the door!
-有钥匙吗  -钥匙
- Well, is there a key? - A key?
没错  关键是找到钥匙
Yes, now, that would be the problem.
凿子客先生
Mr. Jaggerman!
中间那张床的上铺  他负责保管钥匙
Top bunk in the centre. Keeper of the keys.
当心  他不幸地没了眼皮
Careful, mind. He's a restless
睡觉的时候也不安宁
sleeper on account of the tragic loss of his eyelids.
-他眼皮没了  -对
- He lost his eyelids? - Aye.
那次玩纸牌真是很难忘
Now, that was a card game to remember.
你真该亲眼看到
You really had to be there.
丁丁  我本想自己去
I'd do this myself, Tintin,
但是你脚步更轻  不容易弄醒这帮小子
but you've a lighter tread and less chance of waking the boys.
你确定这主意行得通吗
Are you sure this is a good idea?
只要他们都没醒
You've nothing to worry about.
你就没什么可担心的
Provided they all stay asleep.
别离霍布斯先生太近
I wouldn't get too close to Mr. Hobbs.
他的手从不离剃刀
He's very handy with a razor.
离吉契先生也远点
And I'd steer clear of Mr. Gitch.
以前做羊倌的  因为他所谓的畜牧学被解雇了
Sacked as a shepherd on account of his "Animal husbandry."
别去咬三明治
Not the sandwich.
去叼钥匙
The keys!
你是个勇敢的小伙子  丁丁
You're a brave lad, Tintin.
我跟你说  我的心都提到嗓子眼了
My heart was in my mouth, I don't mind telling you.
那个  那个要是我的心的话
Well, that is, if it was my heart.
按我的胃口来说  在嗓眼的指不定是什么
Judging by my stomach, it could've been anything, really.
快点  船长  我们没时间了
Hurry up, Captain! We've no time to lose.
好咧
Bingo!
就拿点必需品
Just the necessities, of course.
去救生艇那
To the lifeboats.
挪进来
Ease it in!
好好干活
Put your back into it!
让它停在那  稳住
Hold her there, steady!
看见他了吗  大块头
Any sign of him, Jumbo?
还没  小心点
Nothing yet. Watch yourself.
老大说他挺棘手
The boss says he's a handful.
这边来
Come on.
那是阿兰
It's Allan.
那是驾驶台吗
Is that the bridge?
是  就在发报房的另一边
Aye, on the other side of the radio room.
发报房
Radio room?
在这等着  船长  有人来就发警报
Wait here, Captain. Sound the alarm if anyone comes.
小心点  丁丁
Careful, Tintin.
我什么都看不着
I can't see a thing!
别抱怨了  找到那男孩
Quit your whining and find the kid!
我不是干这个的
I didn't sign on for this!
继续找
Keep searching!
刚有消息过来了  老大
Message just come through, boss.
什么消息
What's it say?
"米兰妮丝·南丁格尔已到达
"The Milanese Nightingale has landed.
准备就绪等待行动"
Waiting in the wings for action."
米兰妮丝·南丁格尔
"Milanese Nightingale"?
希望这消息能让他高兴
Now pray this cheers him up.
百佳
"Bagghar."
这是什么
What's this?
百佳的领土
"The Sultanate of Bagghar
由奥玛·本·萨拉德酋长统治
"Ruled over by Sheikh Omar Ben Salaad,
"他热爱音乐  文化
"Whose love of music and
尤其钟爱..."
culture is matched only by his love of..."
我的天哪
Great snakes!
百佳
Bagghar.
百佳港
The Port of Bagghar.
在摩洛哥
Morocco.
丁丁
Tintin!
你  举起手来
Hey! Put your hands up!
这下可给你个教训
And let that be a lesson to you!
救命
Help me!
在这  他在这
In here! He's in here!
他在这  在救生艇这
Here! By the lifeboats!
滚开
Out of the way!
去追他  抓住他
After him! Get him!
快  快  在这呢
Quick, quick, in here!
在那边
Over there!
怎么回事  你个小...
Why, you little...
-他在上面  -上
- He's up there! - Go!
我看见他了
I can see him now!
别让他跑了
Don't let them get away!
救命啊
Help me!
-掉头  -是  长官
- Turn this ship around! - Aye, sir!
给我一个照明弹
Get me a flare!
船长  躺下  快躺下
Captain, get down! Get down!
-他在那  -给我让开
- There he is! - Get out of the way!
全速前进  全速前进
Now! Full ahead! Full speed!
你们死定了
Got you now.
躺下
Stay down.
看  看下面
Look! Down there!
蠢货  一群蠢货  你们都干了什么
Idiots! You idiots! What have you done?
我们把他们杀了  老大  如您所愿
We killed them, boss, like you wanted!
不  才不如我所愿  我要阿道克活着
No! Not like I wanted! I needed Haddock alive!
等一下  老大  有两艘长艇不见了
Wait a minute, boss! There are two boats missing!
那被毁的这艘肯定是伪装的
So, that one must have been a decoy.
他们对我们很了解  知道我们的目的地
They're onto us, and our destination.
找到他们  确保他们决不会到达百佳
Find them! Make absolutely certain they never reach Bagghar!
是  老大
Yes, boss.
上来
Get up there!
我们得赶在萨卡林之前赶到百佳
We have to get to Bagghar ahead of Sakharine.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
为什么
Why?
因为他知道第三个模型的下落
Because he has the third model ship.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
酋长收集古老的船只
The Sheikh collects old ships. And this
而这个是他收藏中的精品
is the prize of his collection.
我的天老爷啊  这是独角兽号
Blistering blue barnacles, that is the Unicorn!
船长  你发现图片上模型四周有点失真吗
Captain, do you see the distortion around the model?
嗯
Aye.
这说明本·萨拉德把它放在一个
It means that Ben Salaad exhibits
防弹玻璃箱里然后陈列在他的宫殿里
it in a bulletproof glass case in his palace.
萨卡林准备把它偷走
And Sakharine is going there to steal it!
对  他有秘密武器
Yes, he has a secret weapon.
就是米兰妮丝·南丁格尔
The Milanese Nightingale.
但光有这些无法解谜
But that won't be enough to solve the mystery,
所以萨卡林还需要你
and that is why Sakharine needs you.
所以他把你囚禁起来
That's why he made you his prisoner.
他需要你记忆中的某些东西
There is something he needs you to remember.
我不明白
I don't follow you.
我在一本书上读到过
I read it in a book.
只有真正的阿道克家族的人才能解开独角兽之谜
That only a true Haddock can discover the secret of the Unicorn.
我一丝一毫都不记得
I don't remember anything about anything.
但是你一定了解你的祖先吧
But you must know about your ancestors,
弗朗西斯爵士  这是你的家族传统
Sir Francis. It's your family legacy!
我的记性不比以前了
My memory is not what it used to be.
-那从前是什么样的  -我忘了
- Well, what did it used to be? - I've forgotten.
船长
Captain,
你能带我们去百佳吗
can you get us to Bagghar?
这算哪门子蠢问题
What sort of a stupid question is that?
把桨给我
Give me those oars!
我给你看看什么叫航海技术  小伙子
I'll show you some real seamanship, laddie.
你这长着一撮红毛的小个子带着条烦人的破狗
I'll not be doubted by some
也敢来怀疑我的本事
pipsqueak tuft of ginger and his irritating dog!
我是大海的主宰
I am master and commander of the seas!
我对大海的了解比对我亲妈脸上长了几颗痣还清楚
I know these waters better than the warts on my mother's face!
看看这一对  睡得倒快
Look at the pair of them. Fast asleep.
典型的旱鸭子  一点毅力都没有
Typical landlubbers. Aye, no stamina these days.
别担心  我肯定把你带到那  丁丁
Never mind. I'll get you there, Tintin.
看  汤姆森  那家伙在那
Look, Thomson. There's the fellow.
天哪
Oh, my.
-希尔克先生吗  -是
- Mr. Silk? - Yes?
-我是汤普森  -我是汤姆森
- My name is Thompson. - And Thomson.
-我们是警察  -我们是警察
- We're police officers! - We're police officers!
哎呀妈呀
Oh, crumbs.
好家伙
Good gracious!
-希尔克先生  -希尔克先生
- Mr. Silk! - Mr. Silk!
-天哪天哪  -您还好吗
- Dear, oh, dear, oh, dear. - Are you okay?
可怜的家伙
Poor fellow!
-您还好吗  -您还好吗  先生
- Are you all right? - Are you all right, sir?
-让我来帮您吧  -谢谢  您真是好人
- Here, let me help you up. - Thank you, that's very kind.
-不要跑  先生  -您看
- No need to run away, sir. - No, no, you see,
昨天我们差点逮到
yesterday we very nearly caught
那个在镇子上横行的小偷
the pickpocket who's been terrorising the town!
小偷
Pickpocket?
我们把他的外套拽下来了
We pulled his jacket off and
在里面发现了一个钱包
inside we found a wallet.
钱包里有您的名字和地址
A wallet with your name and address!
-那是我的钱包  -显然是从您这偷的
- That's my wallet. - Well, it's obvious he stole it from you.
不  不  那是我的钱包
No, no, that's my wallet.
您还好吗  先生
Are you all right, sir?
我们并不想吓着您
We didn't mean to startle you.
让我们帮您开门吧
Let us help you into your apartment.
太感谢了  你们就不用进来了
Thank you so much. No need to come in.
我没问题  真的
I'll be quite all right, really.
不  我们一定要进来
No, we insist.
失礼好过出错
Better safe than sorry.
-我们最起码保证您的安全  -谢谢
- It's the least we can do. - Thank you.
请坐
There we are.
我的天哪  这都是什么
Good grief! What's all this?
是我的收藏
It's my collection?
-这么多钱包  -我也没办法
- What a lot of wallets! - I can't help it.
开始只收集零钱袋
It started with coin
后来就一发不可收拾了  真的
purses and sort of went on from there, really.
你得小心点  没听说吗
You want to be careful. Haven't you heard?
这正闹小偷呢
There's a pickpocket about.
你想想他要是看见这么多钱包可高兴了
Yes, he'd love this. Can you imagine?
你说"小偷"是什么意思
What do you mean, "Pickpocket"?
一个犯罪大师
A master criminal.
一个掏人兜  偷人包
A bag-snatching, purse-pilfering,
顺人钱的偷偷摸摸的小贼
wallet-lifting sneak thief!
我不是坏人啊
I'm not a bad person.
我就是有盗窃癖
I'm a kleptomaniac.
-有什么  -就是对开放空间恐惧
- A what? - It's a fear of open spaces.
可怜的家伙
Poor man.
怪不得他把钱包都放在起居室里
No wonder he keeps his wallets in the living room.
钱包嘛
Wallets.
我就是抗拒不了这些可爱的小东西
I just can't resist the lovely little things.
这就是个无害的小爱好  真的
It's a harmless little habit, really.
老天爷啊  汤姆森  看这个
Good heavens, Thomson, look at this!
他的名字也叫汤普森
His name's Thompson, too.
真巧啊
What a coincidence.
不  汤姆森  我是汤姆森  不是那个"不靠谱"的"普"
No, Thomson, this is Thomson without a "P," As in "Psychic."
不不不  是汤普森  就是"科普"的
No, no, no, it's Thompson with a "P," As in "Psychologist."
看看这个  这个绿钱包是我在一个扒手
Look at this one! A green one that I managed to pick
扒别人口袋的时候从他身上扒来的
from a pickpocket actually pickpocketing at the time.
-还有这个  猪皮的  -你说的不对
- And this one! Cuir de cochon. - No, you have it all wrong.
就是"不靠谱"的"普"
There is a "P" In "Psychic."
我才不是不靠谱  你才是
I am not your sidekick! You are mine!
来闻一下吧  真正猪皮
Smell it, won't you? Piggy leather!
你大错特错
No, you have it all wrong.
-你不要脸  -你不要脸
- How dare you! - How dare you!
-是我先遇见你的  -是我先遇见你的
- I met you first. - I met you first.
-根本不是  -本来就是
- No, you didn't. - Yes, I did.
-我说不是  -我说就是
- No, you did not. - Yes, I did.
-不是  -就是
- Didn't! - Did!
天哪  我再也受不了了
Listen! I can't stand it any more!
好吧  我乖乖跟你们走
All right, I'll come quietly.
拿走吧  拿走吧  都拿走吧
Take them! Take them! Take them all!
干什么  冷静一下
Stop it. Pull yourself together, man!
我们不能拿你的钱包  我们像是小偷吗
We can't take your wallets! Do we look like thieves?
我的天哪  汤普森
Good heavens, Thompson.
这个看起来真眼熟
This looks familiar.
不会吧
Can't be.
没错
It is!
丁丁
9月17日
-是丁丁的  -是丁丁的
- Tintin! - Tintin!
好冷啊
I'm so cold.
真渴啊
And thirsty.
嗓子冒烟了
My throat is parched.
让我找找哪儿有淡水
Let's see if there's any fresh water.
看这是什么
What have we here?
丁丁
Tintin.
伙计  过来暖和暖和吧
Come and warm yourself, laddie.
船长
Captain?
-你都干了些什么  -不用谢了
- What have you done? - No need to thank me.
什么
What?
你看起来有点儿冷  我就生了个小火
Well, you looked a little cold, so I lit a wee fire.
在船上
In a boat?
别  那是桨  不能折了
No! Those are our oars! We need those oars!
没错  反正用不了多久了
Yes, but not for much longer.
你疯了吗  快点儿  船长  快帮忙
Have you gone mad? Quick, Captain, help me!
-快来帮我啊  船长  -没错  我都干了什么
- Captain, help me, quick! - He's right. What have I done?
-我干了什么  -别  船长  别用那个
- What have I done? - No, Captain, not that!
真是场灾难
Thundering typhoons!
这还真是个不错的麻烦
Well, this is a fine mess.
-我是个懦弱的  -我们被困在这里
- I'm weak. - We're stranded here...
-自私自利  -孤立无援
- Selfish. - ...with no hope of rescue...
无药可救
I'm hopeless.
而萨卡林和他的手下离百佳越来越近
...while Sakharine and his men are halfway to Bagghar.
可怜  可悲的混球
Poor, miserable wretch!
行了  够了  别说了
Yes, all right. That's enough of that.
都是他的错  是法郎西斯爵士的错
It was his fault, you see. It was Sir Francis.
这句话从何说起
Tell me, how did you work that one out?
因为他是勇气和胆量的象征
Because he was a figurehead of great courage and bold exploits.
他是我们家族的佼佼者
No one like him ever existed in my family.
知道我为什么嗜酒如命吗
Why do you think I drink?
因为我知道我永远赶不上他
Because I know I'll never be like him.
不如就此了结算了
No, it's far better that I end it now.
把我们俩都从痛苦中解脱出来
Put us both out of our misery.
怎么了  白雪
What is it, Snowy?
我要把自己沉入海底
I'm gonna lower myself into the sea.
这片广阔的大海  张开你冰冷的怀抱吧
Into the cold embrace of the big blue!
是葡萄牙的飞机
Those are Portuguese markings.
-你听见了没有  -卡拉布朗是在哪儿注册的
- Are you even listening? - Where is the Karaboudjan registered?
我们得救了
We're saved.
We're saved!
这是上天的旨意
It's a sign from above!
-这帮山顶洞人  -船长  蹲下
- Troglodytes! - Captain, get down.
没人性的懦夫
Slave-traders! Mutant malingerers!
乡下来的骗子
Freshwater politicians!
坏消息  船长  我们只有一发子弹了
Bad news, Captain. We've only got one bullet.
-那好消息呢  -我们还有一发子弹
- And what's the good news? - We've got one bullet.
打中啦
You got him!
干得好  小伙子
Well done, my boy.
待在这儿别动  船长
Stay here, Captain.
丁丁
Tintin?
-好好盯着他们  -快点儿
- Don't take your eyes off of them. - Hurry up!
果然如此  打火的线被打断了
Just as I thought. The ignition lead has been cut.
瞎猫碰上死耗子
Lucky shot!
再扫荡一轮  他们肯定完蛋
One more pass, and we will finish them off.
举起手来
Put your hands in the air.
快点儿
Now!
飞行员指南
让我看看
Let's see here.
你知道自己在干什么吧  丁丁
You do know what you're doing, eh, Tintin?
多少知道
More or less.
到底是多还是少
Well, which is it? More or less?
别紧张  我以前采访过一个飞行员
Relax. I interviewed a pilot once.
去北非怎么走
Which way to North Africa?
看  船长
Captain, look!
我们赶上他们了
We've caught up with them.
太棒了
Wonderful!
但你是不是能找到另外一条路
But you think we might find another way to North Africa
不用通过那道死亡旋风
that doesn't take us through that Wall of Death?
我们不能回头了
We can't turn back.
现在不行
Not now.
不行  船长  这些是
No, Captain! Those are
医用酒精  不能喝
surgical spirits for medicinal purposes only.
说的没错  伙计  说的没错
Quite right, laddie, quite right.
不不不
No, no, no!
是燃料罐  快空了
The fuel tank! It's almost empty!
船长  这可能有些疯狂  但我有个办法
Captain! This may sound crazy, but I've got a plan.
那个瓶子里的酒精也许还能让我们再飞几英里
The alcohol in that bottle may give us a few more miles.
你得爬出去
I need you to climb out
把它倒进燃料缸里
of the plane and pour it into the fuel tank.
我的祖宗啊
Christopher Columbus!
外头在刮大风
There's a terrible storm out there.
还在下大雨
And it's raining.
你到底是不是姓阿道克的
And you call yourself a Haddock?
船长
Captain!
船长  能听见我说话吗
Captain! Can you hear me?
船长
Captain!
Captain?
很好  现在把酒精倒进去
You're doing fine! Now, pour the bottle into the tank.
我们快没燃料了
We're running on fumes.
燃料
Fumes!
哦  不
Oh, no.
船长  我看不见了
Captain! I can't see!
land还有前面是陆地的意思
着陆  着陆
Land! Land!
不行  我们还没到呢
We can't! We're not there yet!
不是  是陆地
No, land!
不不不  右转舵  右转舵  右转舵
No, no, no, starboard! Starboard! Starboard!
撑住  丁丁
Hang on, Tintin!
我来了
I'm coming!
渴死了渴死了
The Land of Thirst.
-渴死了渴死了  -你能不能别说了
- The Land of Thirst. - Will you stop saying that?
你不明白  我快玩完了
You don't understand. I've run out.
我快玩完了  你不知道这是什么感觉
I've run out. You don't know what that means.
船长  我们得继续走
Captain, we have to keep going.
一步一步往前走  来
One step at a time. Come on,
站起来  靠在我身上
on your feet! Lean your weight on me.
一个人离开了他生命的源泉又能走多久
A man can only hang on so long without his vitals.
船长  别激动  酒醒不是世界末日
Captain, calm down. There are worse things than sobering up.
看  丁丁
Look! Tintin!
我们得救了
We're saved.
水  水
Water. Water!
别去  船长
Stop! Captain!
那是海市蜃楼
It's just a mirage!
刚才还在呢  我看见了
But it was here. I saw it.
那只是错觉  是热气折射的光线
It was just your mind playing tricks. It's the heat!
我得回家去
I have to go home.
-什么  我得回到海上
- What? - I have to go back to the sea.
船长  那都是幻觉
Captain, you're hallucinating.
看
Look.
你见过比这更美的景色吗
Did you ever see a more beautiful sight?
她转向顺风的方向  所有的帆都扬起
She's turning into the wind, all sails set.
三个桅杆
Triple masted.
双层甲板  五十门火炮
Double decks. Fifty guns.
独角兽号
The Unicorn?
-她真是个美人儿  -没错  没错
- Isn't she a beauty? - Yes! Yes, she is!
告诉我  船长  你还看见什么了
Tell me, Captain, what else can you see?
她乘风破浪
She's got the wind behind her.
看她优雅的步伐
Look at the pace she's setting!
Barbados: 拉丁美洲某岛国
刚离开巴巴多斯一天
Barely a day out of Barbados,
她装满了朗姆酒和最好的烟草
a hold full of rum and the finest tobacco
船员们思念家乡  归心似箭
and the hearts of the sailors set for home.
红色的海盗旗
The red pennant.
一看到那个旗
The blood runs cold in
所有船长的心都会一沉
every sea captain who looks upon that flag,
因为他们知道他们将面临一场恶战
for he knows he's facing a fight to the death.
但是法朗西斯爵士与众不同
But Sir Francis is a Haddock.
阿道克家的人不会临阵脱逃
And Haddocks don't flee.
全体船员上甲板  炮手准备
All hands on deck! Gunners to their stations!
让这些懦弱的寄生虫们
Let's unload the King's shot into these
见识一下皇家的威风
yellow-bellied, lily-livered sea slugs!
-准备好掉头了吗  尼克斯先生  -没问题  船长
- Prepare to bring her about, Mr. Nicholls. - Aye-aye, Captain!
准备掉头
Prepare to bring her about!
开火
Fire!
左舷炮手  开火
Portside gun, fire!
招子放亮点  伙计们
Look lively, lads!
-尼克斯先生  看好货物  -好的  先生
- Mr. Nicholls, secure the cargo. - Right you are, sir.
准备击退登船者
Prepare to repel all boarders!
这边儿来  我们人手不够
This way! We need more men!
就在这时  他看见了他
And then he saw him.
就像一个幽灵  从阴间走来
Like a phantom, rising from the dead.
是谁
Who?
船长  他看见了谁
Captain, who did he see?
消失了
It's gone.
什么意思  什么叫消失了  然后呢
What do you mean, gone? What happened next?
好家伙  我居然有胡子  我什么时候留的
By Jupiter, I have a beard! Since when did I have a beard?
船长  独角兽号上发生过一些事情
Captain, something happened on the Unicorn.
是所有问题的关键  你必须努力想起来
It's the key to everything. You must try to remember.
独角兽号  什么  我快渴死了
The Unicorn? What? I'm so terribly thirsty.
-船长  -丁丁
- Captain! - Tintin!
我这是怎么了
What is happening to me?
在撒哈拉待一天你居然就能想起这么多
And to think all it took was a day in the Sahara.
恭喜你  船长  你酒醒了
Congratulations, Captain, you're sober.
酒醒
Sober.
好狗狗
Good dog!
这个还活着
This one's alive.
-去看看那个  -是  长官
- Check the other! - Yes, sir.
全体  立定
Company, halt!
我是戴乐谷中尉  欢迎来到阿法戈哨所
I'm Lieutenant Delcourt. Welcome to the Afghar Outpost.
谢谢你  中尉  多亏你救了我们的命
Thank you, Lieutenant. We owe you our lives.
-你找到我的朋友了吗  -找到了
- Did you find my friend? - Yes,
但恐怕他的状况不太好
but he's not in good shape, I'm afraid.
他因为严重脱水有些神志不清
He's still suffering the effects of acute dehydration. He's quite delirious.
来看看他吧
Why don't we pay him a visit?
阿道克  你醒了
Haddock! You're awake.
很好  有人来看你了
Good! I have a visitor for you.
-船长  -你好
- Captain? - Hello!
我想你走错房间了
I think you've got the wrong room.
船长  是我  丁丁
Captain, it's Tintin.
我们的飞机在沙漠里坠毁了  你不记得了
Our plane crashed in the desert. Don't you remember?
飞机  不不  我是开船的
Plane? No, no, I'm a naval man myself.
只要有可能我绝不碰飞机
I never fly if I can help it.
他认错人了
He's got me confused with someone else.
这独特的液体是什么
What is this peculiar liquid?
没有香味  完全透明
There's no bouquet. It's completely transparent.
这是水啊
Why, it's water.
看他们下次能想出什么瞎话骗我
What will they think of next?
酒精
我们怀疑他得了脑震荡  中暑  精神错乱
We suspect he has a concussion. Heatstroke. Delirium.
他只是酒醒了
He's sober.
船长  在沙漠里的时候
Now, Captain, out in the desert...
-沙漠  -没错  你跟我提到法朗西斯爵士
- The desert? - Yes. You were talking about Sir Francis.
-什么爵士  -法朗西斯爵士
- Sir who? - Sir Francis.
你还跟我说了独角兽号上发生的故事
And you were telling me about what happened on the Unicorn.
-独角兽  -没错
- The unicorn! - Yes!
那东西只是在梦里出现
The stuff that dreams are made of.
小孩子的梦
Wee children's dreams.
不是那个  是船  拜托你想想  船长
No, the ship. Please try to remember, Captain.
人命关天
Lives are at risk.
白雪  你干的好事
Snowy, what have you done?
我要是你就会退后
I'd stand back if I were you.
走  所有人都出去
Out! Everybody out of the room!
白雪
Snowy!
这个人疯了
This man is insane!
现身吧  红巾莱克汗
Show yourself, Red Rackham!
如果你想大战一场  那正好棋逢对手
If it's a fight you want, you've met your match!
和谁大战一场
A fight with who?
红巾莱克汗  去死
To the death, Red Rackham!
别过来  等一下
No, wait!
等一下  船长
Wait. Captain...
我全想起来了
I remember everything now.
爷爷告诉我的一切我都想起来了
Everything Granddaddy told me.
独角兽号被人夺走了
The Unicorn was taken.
那群海盗成了主人
The pirates were now masters of the ship.
船员们都投降了吗
The crew surrendered?
爷爷说红巾莱克汗
Granddaddy said that Red
骂法朗西斯爵士是国王的走狗
Rackham called Sir Francis the King's dog.
是被派来打击海盗  追讨他们来之不易的财宝
A pirate hunter sent to reclaim their hard-won plunder.
我知道你这里有的是更值钱的东西
Why would I waste my time on rum, tobacco, molasses and dates
为什么还要费尽心血抢劫烟酒糖枣
when you have a more valuable cargo onboard?
财宝在哪
Where is it?
除非你先杀了我
You'll have to kill me first.
想得美  不行
Not first, no.
求你了
Please.
我会先杀了你的手下
I'll start with your men.
为了救他的船员
To save his men,
他打算放弃财宝
he would give up the secret cargo.
在哪儿
And where was it?
一英担约合112磅  四英担约203公斤
四英担的金银财宝
Four hundredweight of gold, jewels and treasure.
杀了他的手下
Kill his men!
不  莱克汗  不
No, Rackham! No!
莱克汗  你向我保证过  莱克汗
Rackham, you gave me your word! Rackham!
莱克汗
Rackham!
法朗西斯爵士知道他的末日到了
Sir Francis knew he was doomed.
他会被吊死在最高的横杆上
That he'd be hung from the highest yardarm.
但他们没想到的是
But they didn't reckon on one thing!
法朗西斯爵士是阿道克家族的
Sir Francis was a Haddock.
阿道克家的人总会留一手
And a Haddock always has a trick up his sleeve.
就这样  他向前猛扑过去
And with that, he hurls himself forward!
扑向海盗  就这样徒手扑过去
On the pirates? Like that? Unarmed?
不  不  是扑向了甲板上滚动的一瓶朗姆酒
No! No, on a bottle of rum rolling on the deck.
打开了它  放到嘴边  然后
And he opens it up, and puts it to his lips, and...
然后他停了下来
And then he stops.
没时间喝酒了
"This is no time for drinking,"
他说  我必须保持清醒
He says. "I need all my wits about me."
说着  他放下酒瓶然后...
With that, he puts down the bottle and...
没错  没错  他放下酒瓶
Yes, yes, he puts down the bottle...
抓过一柄弯刀
And he seizes a cutlass.
来到弹药库
And then he makes his way to the ship's magazine,
那里放着所有的火药和炮弹
where they keep all the gunpowder and the shot!
奸诈小人
You dog!
想把我们炸上天吗
You'd blow us sky high?
好吧
Come on, then.
接招
Let's have you.
这次你别想赢
Not this time.
是你
You!
船长  怎么了
Captain, what is it?
我怎么会没看出来
How could I be so blind?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
这不光是为了纸卷
This isn't just about the scrolls or...
和随船一起沉入海底的宝藏
Or the treasure that went down with the ship.
还有我
It's me.
他也在追杀我
It's me he's after!
我诅咒你和你的家族  阿道克
You'll suffer a curse upon you and your name, Haddock.
他想要报仇
He wants vengeance.
回来  看着我
Come back and face me!
-快走  丁丁  -什么
- Hurry, Tintin. - What?
-快来不及了  -船长
- We're out of time. - Captain!
我诅咒你
I curse you!
我诅咒你的姓氏和你的子子孙孙
I curse your name and all who come after!
我们还会再见的  阿道克
We will meet again, Haddock!
下一次  下辈子
In another time! In another life!
还没有结束  远远没有结束
It's not over. It was never over!
我不明白  是谁在追杀你
I don't understand. Who's after your blood?
-萨卡林  -萨卡林  为什么
- Sakharine! - Sakharine? Why?
他是红巾莱克汗的后代  他要结束这一切
He's Red Rackham's descendent! He means to finish it!
-所以他才那么做  -什么意思
- That's why he did it. - Did what?
弄沉自己的船  法朗西斯爵士
Sank his own ship. Sir Francis
把宝藏送入海底
sent that treasure to the bottom of the sea.
在红巾莱克汗拿到宝藏前他会一直受诅咒
He would be damned before he let Red Rackham have it.
-的确是  -但他不能就让它沉在那儿
- And he was. - But he couldn't let it lie.
-不能  -他留下了线索
- No. - He left a clue.
三条线索暗含在谜语中  暗藏着秘密
Three clues wrapped in a riddle, concealing a secret.
但只有真正的阿道克家的人才能揭开谜底
But only a true Haddock would be able to solve it.
-什么谜底  -地点
- What secret? - The location.
埋藏着历史上最大的沉没宝藏的地点
To one of the greatest sunken treasures in all history.
独角兽号沉船的位置
The wreck of the Unicorn.
他想要偷走它  第三个纸卷
He means to steal it! The third scroll!
这下玩大了
Billions of blue, blistering barnacles!
我发誓  作为阿道克家唯一的后代
I swear, as the last of the Haddocks,
我一定要在他之前找到它
I'll find that treasure before him!
去百佳
To Bagghar.
他也来了
He's here.
情况不妙啊  他们可能在任何地方
It's no good. They could be anywhere.
船长
Captain.
别回头  咱们被人跟踪了
Don't look now, but we're being followed.
没错
Yes, we are.
你们想干什么  为什么跟踪我们
What do you want? Why are you following us?
你们为谁跑腿
Who are you working for?
船长  停手  停手
Captain, stop! Stop!
是汤普森和汤姆森
Thompson and Thomson.
别这么大声
Not so loud.
-我们是乔装的  -看出来了
- We're in disguise. - So I see.
你们收到我从船上发的消息了
You got the message I sent from the ship?
是的  说来话长
Yes, well, bit of a long story, that.
简单说我们抓到了偷你钱包的贼
The upshot is we caught the thief, retrieved your wallet,
然后立马坐上了来百佳的飞机
and then hopped on the next plane to Bagghar.
没错  那个小偷也被抓了起来
Yes, that pocket picker has picked his last pocket.
给  别担心  一分钱都没丢
There. Don't worry. He didn't take any money.
我不是在担心钱
It's not the money I'm worried about.
现在是平局了
The odds are even.
我们去找剩下的两个密卷
Now, to find the next two scrolls.
米兰妮丝·南丁格尔
The Milanese Nightingale.
这就是他的秘密武器
That's his secret weapon?
-天  -上帝
- My! - My!
多么美丽
What a dish.
迷人的夫人
Enchanted, signora!
欢迎到来
Benvenuto! Welcome! Marhaba!
因为您的出现我们倍受祝福
We are blessed with your presence.
谢谢  萨拉德酋长
Yes. Indeed, Signor Salad!
您的农庄也非常美丽
What charming peasants.
允许我来介绍下我的护卫
May I introduce my escort,
舒格勒·阿德提夫先生
Monsieur Shuggair Addeitiff.
他尽心尽力的
He's been very
支持这次演唱会
passionate in his support of this concert.
这是我第一次来到第三世界国家
It's my first visit to the Third World.
很抱歉  我必须
Please forgive me. I must
先护送夫人去更衣室  失陪
escort madame to her dressing room. Excuse us.
夫人先请
After you.
防弹玻璃
-你好  -你好
- Hello, how are you? - Hello...
给  我要你收好这个
Here. I want you to look after this.
-你怎么了  -我
- What are you doing? - Me?
-是  -你确定吗
- Yes. - Are you sure?
如果我被抓了  这东西不能让他们找到
If I'm caught, I don't want them to find this on me.
听着  一定要把这个藏好
Look, just keep it hidden.
我会用生命保护它
I will guard this with my life!
起来  起来
Get up! Get up!
她来了
It's her!
老天啊
Blistering barnacles!
这是什么歌声
What's that noise?
我的耳朵
My ears,
-流血了  -不  没有流血
- they're bleeding. - No, they're not.
船长
Captain.
安静  白雪
Shut up, Snowy.
老天  我得逃命  请让让
Oh, Columbus, it's every man for himself! Make way.
让下  我很难受
Make way! Medical emergency.
差点忍不住
That was close.
你好  船长
Hello, Captain.
是你
You!
不好
Oh, no!
萨卡林
Sakharine!
猎鹰  白雪  跟上它
The falcon! Snowy, after him!
丁丁
Tintin! Tintin!
那两个人  他们要偷走你的船
Those two! There! They're here to steal your ship!
不  我们不是
No, no, no, no, no, we're not!
抓住他  那个丑鬼
Arrest him! The ugly one!
-不是  等下  -谁  你说我
- No, wait! - Who, me?
没错
Yes!
小偷  抓住他
Thief! Arrest him!
船长
Captain!
-萨卡林拿到密卷了  -还有更糟的
- Sakharine's got the scroll! - It's worse than that.
-什么意思  -你的也被他抢走了  丁丁  被抢走了
- What do you mean? - They took your scroll, Tintin. It's gone.
怎么可能  怎么回事
How? What happened?
是阿兰
It was Allan.
他在花园拦住了我
He knobbled me in the garden, and then
-那里正好有瓶酒  -又是酒
- there was a bottle of alcohol and... - There always is.
不  和你想的不一样
No, no! No, not like that.
我都闻到酒味了
I can smell it on you.
快  咱们回船上
Hurry. Back to the boat.
-丁丁  你要去哪  -去追萨卡林
- Tintin! Where are you going? - I'm going after Sakharine.
-你自己去  -是的
- By yourself? - Yes!
快跟上  白雪
Come on, Snowy!
抓住他们  抓住他们
Catch them, catch them!
干掉他们  甩掉这个讨厌的尾巴
Lose them! Get him off our tail!
你打到了什么吗
Did you hit anything?
妈呀
Oh, dear.
快点  笨蛋  快开
Faster, you idiot, faster!
这次你跑不了了
Not again!
-我拿走了  谢谢  -快回来  白雪
- I'll have those, thank you. - Come on, Snowy!
不
No!
那只猎鹰又来了  四点钟方向
Incoming falcon at four o'clock!
丁丁  快开
Tintin, faster!
-纸卷  -一个  两个
- The scrolls! - I got one, two...
三个
And three!
白雪
Snowy!
不是吧  又来
Oh, no! Not again.
飘过来  宝贝
Come here, my beauty.
真是倒霉透了
Ten thousand thundering typhoons!
别跑  你这只偷人的长尾巴鸟
Come here, you pilfering parakeet!
船长  快抓住那只鸟
Captain, the bird! Grab it!
干得漂亮  白雪  别让它跑了
Nice work, Snowy! Don't let him go!
你个招人烦的讨厌鬼
You blue blistering barnacles!
坚持住  白雪  我来了
Hang on, Snowy! Snowy, I'm coming!
它在这  停车
There he is! Stop!
干得好  好样的  到爸爸这来
That's right, that's right, come to Daddy.
到爸爸这
Come to Daddy.
抓到了
Gotcha!
不
No!
我来啦
Geronimo!
你这个背后捅刀子  只会偷东西的寄生虫
You double-dealing, pilfering parasites!
打扰了  非常抱歉
Excuse me. Pardon me. Sorry.
抓到了
Gotcha!
把纸条重叠在一起
The scrolls are lining up.
上面有隐藏的数字
These are hidden numbers.
这说的什么
What does it say?
如果我是你  我就会停手
I wouldn't do that if I were you!
放开我的鸟
Let the bird go.
你想要哪个  阿道克的命  还是那三张纸条
What do you value more, those scrolls or Haddock's life?
别听他的
Don't listen to him.
你永远别想得到纸条  你个苦逼相的英国佬
You'll never get away with this, you sour-faced sassonack!
我要杀了他
I will kill him.
别担心我  丁丁  我没事
Don't worry about me, Tintin, I'm fine.
马上放开鸟  要不这人就死定了
Let the bird go now, or this man dies!
不  等等
No! Wait!
你这个骗人的山顶洞人
You two-timing troglodyte!
还有你  笑里藏刀的奸商龟儿子
You simpering son of a po-faced profiteer!
也许该把你推下去试试  祝你好运
Perhaps we should put it to the test. Here's mud in your eye.
你个混蛋
Fathead!
船长
Captain!
百佳酒店
-我们得救了  -我喜欢海边
- We're saved! - I love the beach.
-你说过想度假  -是啊
- You said you wanted a holiday. - Quite.
非常好
Very good.
-没人能抢走我的船  -他们已经抢走了
- Nobody takes my ship! - They've already taken it.
没人能抢走我的船两次
Nobody takes my ship twice!
我们该给他们颜色瞧瞧
We'll show them, won't we,
丁丁  接下来的计划是什么
Tintin? All right then, what's the plan?
没计划
There is no plan.
你当然有计划  你总偶计划
Of course there's a plan. You've always got a plan.
这次没了
Not this time.
萨卡林拿到了所有密卷  将会找到宝藏
Sakharine has the scrolls. They'll lead him to the treasure.
宝藏可能在世界任何角落
It could be anywhere in the world.
我们不会再见到他了
We'll never see him again.
都结束了
It's over.
我一直认为你是个乐观主义者
I thought you were an optimist.
你说错了  我是个现实主义者
Well, you were wrong, weren't you? I'm a realist.
这是懦夫的代名词
That's just another name for a quitter.
随你怎么说
You can call me what you like.
你还不明白吗  我们失败了
Don't you get it? We failed.
失败
"Failed."
任何人都可以嘲笑你是个失败者
There are plenty of others willing to call you a failure.
说你是白痴  笨蛋  醉鬼
A fool. A loser. A hopeless souse!
但唯独你自己不行
Don't you ever say it of yourself.
你发出错误的信号
You send out the wrong signal.
别人就接收到了
That is what people pick up.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
你在乎某件事  就要为之奋斗
You care about something, you fight for it.
撞上墙又怎样  推倒它继续前进
You hit a wall, you push through it.
丁丁  对于失败你必须明白
There's something you need to know about failure, Tintin.
你不能被它打倒
You can never let it defeat you.
你刚说的什么
What did you just say?
撞上墙  就推倒它继续前进
You hit a wall, you push through it.
不不  你刚说给一个什么信号
No, no, no, you said something about sending out a signal.
对了  船长
Of course! Captain!
我曾经从卡拉布朗上发过电报
I sent a radio message from the Karaboudjan.
我还记得他们所用的频率
I know what radio frequency they're transmitting on.
这对咱有什么帮助
Well, how does that help us?
我们要做的就是告诉国际刑警
All we have to do is send that information to Interpol,
他们能追踪这个信号
they can track the signals
然后找到他们的下落
and figure out which way they're headed.
刚说到刑警  他们就来了
Here comes Interpol now.
-丁丁  -丁丁
- Tintin! - Tintin!
只要他们进了任何一个港口  我们就能马上知道
Any port they enter we'll know at once.
而且我们可以先到达那里
And we can get there first.
老板  我们要做什么  我不太明白
What are we doing here, boss? I don't get it.
我们又跑回出发地干吗
We're right back where we started.
闭上嘴  别让人知道我们回来了
You're to speak of this to no one. Keep your mouths shut.
没问题  只要我们能拿到分成
Don't worry. As long as we get our share.
你们会拿到的
You'll get your share.
-你要去哪里  -你们只管看好船
- Where are you going? - Just guard the ship.
钱在哪
Where's the filthy moolah?
晚上好  先生  相信您旅途一定很愉快
Good evening, sir. I trust you had a successful trip abroad.
我花钱让你跟我废话吗
Do I pay you to talk to me?
你根本就没给我钱
You don't pay me at all.
怎么回事  奈斯特
What the blazes? Nestor!
奈斯特
Nestor!
汤姆  阿兰
Tom! Allan!
你们这两个笨蛋   别杵在那里  做点什么
You blithering idiots, don't just stand there! Do something!
就像抓陷阱中的老鼠一样
Caught him like a rat in a trap.
恭喜  先生们  他现在是你们的了
Congratulations, gentlemen. He's all yours.
联邦调查局和国际刑警
Yes! We also have an arrest
都对他派发了逮捕令
warrant issued by both Interpol and the FBI.
-你那个被射杀的朋友  -巴纳比
- Your friend who got shot... - Barnaby.
他也是他们派遣的一名特工
he was one of their agents.
一直负责追查萨卡林的行踪
Hot on Sakharine's trail from the start.
这仍然说不动
It still doesn't make sense.
他已经知道了找到独角兽号上财宝的关键
He has the key to the treasure of the Unicorn,
那肯定是藏在海底的某处
which is sitting somewhere on the ocean floor.
为什么他却要回家呢
Why would he come back home?
好了
Right.
-萨卡林  -萨卡林
- Sakharine? - Sakharine?
请尊称我先生
That's Mr. Sakharine to you.
把手举起来
Hold it.
-小心  -什么
- Look out! - What...
不要
Oh, no!
阿兰  阿兰  快放我下去
Allan! Allan, get me down!
什么  不是那个方向
What? Not that way!
方向错了  你个白痴  反向  反向
Not that way, you fool, the other way!
好的
Right.
小心
Look out!
好家伙  这边走
Good Lord! Come on!
还差点
Close but no cigar!
-红巾莱克汗  -没错  他是我的祖先
- Red Rackham! - That's right. My ancestor.
就像弗朗西斯爵士是你的祖先一样
Just as Sir Francis was yours.
家族恩怨还未了结
Unfinished business.
我很开心你知道真相  阿道克
I'm glad you know the truth, Haddock. Until you could remember,
直到你记起来  杀了你才有意义
killing you wouldn't have been this much fun.
谁允许你登上我的船了
Who gave you permission to board my ship?
我不需要许可
I don't need it.
从来就不需要
I've never needed it.
传说只有真正的阿道克
The legend says only a
才能揭开独角兽号的秘密
Haddock can discover the secret of the Unicorn,
不过看来是莱克汗做到了
but it took a Rackham to get the job done.
阿道克  你又失败了
So you've lost again, Haddock.
没错  你现在怎么不来一杯呢
That's right. Why don't you have a drink?
你不是最擅长喝酒吗
That's all you've got left, isn't it?
本该是你的一切都属于我了
Everything that was rightfully yours is now mine.
包括这艘船
Including this ship.
去你奶奶个腿  没人敢抢走我的船
Thundering typhoons. Nobody takes my ship.
你落网了  混蛋
We have you now, you devil.
-你被捕了  -更准确地说
- You are under arrest. - To be precise,
你被捕了
you are under arrest.
到了吗
Do you see?
老天啊  这是一个坐标
Blistering barnacles, they're coordinates.
三张纸条叠在一起
It took all three scrolls
-就会形成数字  -经度和纬度
- to form the numbers. - Latitude and longitude.
就是这个  这就是宝藏的地点
That is it. That's the location of the treasure.
我们做到了
We did it!
快到了  丁丁
Almost there, Mr. Tintin!
稍微偏右转舵就行了
A nudge to starboard should do it.
-你确定航向正确吗  -相信我  伙计
- Are you sure we're on course? - Trust me, laddie.
我对方位了如指掌
I know these parts like the back of my hand.
右转舵   快  快
Starboard! Quickly! Quickly!
没问题  船长  右转舵
Aye, Captain, starboard it is!
停船抛锚
All stop!
马林斯派克别墅
Marlinspike Hall.
坐标指的原来是这里
Those coordinates lead here.
弗朗西斯爵士会把财宝藏在这里吗
And this is where Sir Francis hid it?
我觉得财宝是跟着船一起沉了
I thought the treasure went down with the ship.
阿道克先生  丁丁  我恭候你们多时了
Master Haddock, Mr. Tintin, I've been expecting you.
欢迎来到马林斯派克别墅
Welcome to Marlinspike Hall.
你看看这里
Will you look at this place?
不敢相信  这还保留着我小时候见到的样子
I don't think it's changed at all since I was a wee boy.
恕我直言  先生  我已期盼很久
And may I say, sir, how much I'm looking forward
能有一位阿道克后人接管这地产
to having a Haddock back in charge of the estate.
奈斯特  恐怕你还得等很久
You'll be waiting a long time, Nestor.
我可没钱能买下这里
There's no way I could afford to live here!
船长  你了解这房子吧
Well, Captain, you know the house.
我们从哪开始找
Where do we start?
这应该有个地窖
Is the cellar still here?
不对  不是这个地窖
No, no, no, no, this isn't it.
我记得还有一个
I meant the other cellar.
抱歉  先生  这房子只有这一个地窖
I'm sorry, sir, there is no "Other cellar."
那个地窖比这个大得多
It was bigger than this.
白雪
Snowy.
白雪  你跑哪里去了
Snowy, where are you?
别这样  赫克托
No, Hector.
赫克托
Hector.
船长  帮下我
Captain, help me.
往边上搬
Heel, boy.
白雪
Snowy?
船长  就像你说的
Just like you said, Captain.
撞上墙
You hit a wall...
就推倒它继续前进
you push through it.
我的爷爷一定是在他失去这座房子前
My grandfather must have walled it up
就将这边封堵上了
before he lost the house.
照耀鹰之十字
"And then shines forth the Eagle's Cross."
我看到了十字架  但鹰在哪
Well, I can see the cross, but where's the eagle?
圣约翰是个传教士
St. John the Evangelist,
据描述  他总带着一只鹰
who was always depicted with an eagle.
所以人们都叫他帕特摩斯之鹰
And he's called the Eagle of Patmos.
鹰指的就是他
He is the eagle.
他试图告诉我们什么呢  船长
What's he trying to tell us, Captain?
我搞不清楚
I'm at a loss.
看这座岛  就中间这个  是不存在的
That island, the one in the middle, that doesn't exist.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为我在那块水域航行过无数次
Because I've sailed those waters countless times.
我去过那里  这图画错了
I've been there. It's a mistake.
如果没错呢
What if it isn't?
弗朗西斯爵士一定希望他的遗产
Sir Francis wanted his
能被一个值得拥有它的人得到
inheritance to go to a man who was worthy of it.
一个像他那样的男人
A man like himself,
对于大海了如指掌的男人
who knows the seas like the back of his hand.
一个一眼就能看出
A man who could look at a globe
地球仪上某个小岛
and tell if one tiny island
根本不存在的男人
was out of place.
全是价值连城的财宝
Blistering treasure.
红巾莱克汗的宝藏
It's Red Rackham's barnacles!
这是什么
What is this?
只喝一点
Just a wee tipple.
为我们的财宝干杯
A toast to our good fortune.
感觉真棒
That's better.
真奇怪  你会想
It's odd, really. You would've thought,
经过这么多麻烦和困扰  应该不止这些
after all the fuss and bother, there would've been more.
-什么不止这些  -红巾莱克汗的宝藏
- More of what? - Red Rackham's treasure.
按你的说法
I mean, by your account,
他洗劫了半个南美洲  所以我想...
he looted half of South America. I just thought...
算了  现在到手的也不少
Never mind. There's plenty to go around.
真是一段难忘的日子  是吧
It's a funny old life, eh?
你也拿到了想要发表的故事
Well, you've got your story for your newspaper.
一切都圆满结束了
All's well that ends well.
还没结束
It's not ended.
法朗西斯爵士在地球仪里留下了另一个线索
Sir Francis left another clue at the bottom of the globe.
-什么的线索  -四英担的黄金
- A clue to what? - Four hundredweight of gold,
就躺在海底的某处
just lying at the bottom of the sea.
船长  你对冒险的渴望还有多少
How's your thirst for adventure, Captain?
永不满足  丁丁
Unquenchable, Tintin.